♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
I want to say goodbye to all of you.
Take care of yourself, Ibyang, okay?
[Karla] Study well. Don't be like me.
[Ibyang] Thank you for everything, Tatoy.
[sobs]
I love you, Tatoy!
[Atoy] What are you still doing here?
Huh?
Your mother is waiting.
You need to go to her.
‪PREVIOUSLY
[Ibyang sobs] Tatoy…
I just want to hug you again.
[sobs]
[Atoy] You'll always be stitched
right here in my heart.
[Red] As long as we have Ibyang,
Atoy can't do anything against us.
Eventually, the child
has to be disposed of.
What do you mean, disposed of?
Get rid of her, so there's no trace.
[Charmi] Have you thought about it?
Where could Ibyang's real mother be?
Now you ask,
when you already have the money.
Forget it.
Is Atoy there?
[Emerson] We are just drowning
his sadness. He invited us.
Fried dumpling,
with vinegar and sweet sauce.
That's what you should buy.
[Olga] You opened
the imported corned beef?!
Oh, no! Why did you do that?!
Just like that,
they're suddenly taken away.
I can handle being alone.
[Gonzales, in English] I was ordered
by Colonel Mercado to meet you
and deliver his directives.
[Samir, in English] I want you to find out
everything about this man.
[in English] Then, we will find him.
[in English] I'm sure
he is looking for the decoder.
[music swells]
♪ Fix this ♪
[Olga] Oh, and now you're crying?!
It's your fault!
[sobbing]
I'm sorry.
[sobs]
Tatoy taught me that the house
should always be tidy.
I'm not your father!
We're different, okay?!
[Olga] Go on!
[utensil clatters]
[sighs] Let's not waste
this meal you cooked.
You're so young yet you already know
how to do so many things.
Do you know how to do laundry?
Yes.
Sis Ame and I used to do laundry together.
[Ibyang] Mama. May I ask something?
No.
Then, just tell me a story.
Where is my father?
Why aren't you with him?
- [scoffs]
- Do I have a grandmother?
What's your favorite color?
[sneaky music playing]
You're good at segueing questions, huh.
Anyway, you don't have a father!
Okay?
Do you want Tatoy instead?
He's single now.
Hmm?
With that handsome face?
[Ibyang] He's just grumpy.
And he does a lot of strange things.
What else does a tailor do?
[music fades]
[Mercado] Padua,
you have a follow-up mission.
I sent Lieutenant Gonzales
to hand you a device.
This is the device I extracted
from the Zahran embassy, sir.
Why is this here again?
[Mercado] I'll send you
the mission details.
But this laptop is for safekeeping
until you find Ms. Lily Santiago,
who is in charge of this device.
[in English] All right. Copy, sir.
Thank you, Padua.
[in English] I will keep you posted
as soon as possible.
[in English] Copy, sir.
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[sewing machine clacking]
[gunshots]
[music swells]
Ibyang used to do that.
She helped me carry the groceries.
But actually, she was just waiting
for rice cakes as a treat.
[chuckles]
And also, she was really kind.
That's why I miss her.
Even if she was a bit naughty,
she was still kind.
I hope Olga is taking good care of her.
Oh, you're here.
Well, miss, even though
we're not related by blood,
we grew to love that girl so much.
So, her real mother
must love her even more.
[sighs]
Oh!
How's Atoy?
Good thing you don't have a hangover
from last night's drinking.
- Ah. It ended early.
- Huh?
Because his boss sent someone.
He has a new assignment.
And he accepted it.
Maybe to distract himself
from Ibyang leaving.
Ah. Oh.
Are you Miss Cita?
Ah…
Yes, that's me. Who are you--
- Please, help me!
- [stammering]
Please, help us!
[Emerson] Wait, wait.
You were referred to us
by your former client.
The one who looked
for his child who eloped.
He said you have contact
with the Master Cutter.
- You?! You're the Master Cutter?!
- [quirky sting]
- Master Cutter, help us!
- Oh!
No, I'm not.
No, no. I'm not.
- Oh.
- [sobs]
Oh, oh, come inside.
[sobs]
Come in.
- [sobbing]
- [muttering]
My child…
[in English] I have a surprise for you!
[in English] Are you ready?
[Audrey] Open it.
[in English] What's this?
[in English] Open it!
[in English] It's your passport!
Really, Mommy?!
So, when are we leaving?
Once we get your visa.
[in English] I already
applied for it online.
From there, it will be fast.
- I'll finally see snow in real life!
- [Audrey chuckles]
Child.
Do you want to say goodbye to your daddy?
[in English] No.
Come on, child.
At least call him.
[in English] You…
You might not see each other…
again.
It's okay.
He's bad anyway.
He hurt Grandpa, right?
My child.
[in English] That was an accident.
Because he wanted to hurt Uncle Red.
He's still bad.
I never felt his love for me.
[inhales] So, it's okay
if we don't say goodbye to him.
[pensive music playing]
He loves you, Janine.
Believe me.
[somber music playing]
[in English] Okay.
[pensive music playing]
Go ahead, eat.
[music fades]
Drink first.
[woman sniffles]
We came here
because we're so desperate, Miss Cita.
[sobbing]
We're the administrators
of the Build for Kids organization.
We have a project to build
a school in Zambales.
We already gathered money from sponsors.
[wails]
But we lost the money we saved.
It was stolen.
[wails]
[somber music playing]
You should go to the police
so those responsible can be charged.
[sobs]
We already did.
But the investigator said
our lead was a dead end.
Ah.
We just want to recover the money.
We don't want this to become a news item
because we don't want to lose
the trust of our sponsors.
[clears throat]
So, ah, how much money
are we talking about here?
[in English] Five million! [wails]
- [in English] Five million pesos?!
- [in English] Five million?
So please, help us.
For the sake of the children
who'll lose their chance to study
if the school doesn't get built.
[sobs]
Oh my God.
That's such a huge amount--
[suspicious music playing]
But the Master Cutter
isn't here right now.
He already has another assignment.
It's over! We have no hope
of recovering it.
[sobs]
[clears throat] Uh…
Uh, well…
[stutters]
Uh, maybe, ah--
[titters]
Maybe… Maybe--
[stutters]
Ah… Calm down.
We'll try to contact another tracker.
Uh, maybe he can help you.
Please stop crying. Stop crying.
Huh?
Who?
‪[quirky sting]
The…
The… The son.
The son… son of the thread.
That! That's the one…
He was also trained by the Master Cutter.
[stammers] Maybe he can help you
recover your money.
Really? Oh, thank you.
[in English] Thank you.
[in English] Thank you. Thank you!
[in English] Thank you! Thank you!
[giggles]
[titters]
Calm down, calm down.
Yes… Yes, okay.
[sneaky music playing]
‪[quirky sting]
Son of the thread?
Oh, all right. We'll update you, okay?
- Thank you very much.
- Okay.
Take care.
- [in English] Thank you.
- Thank you.
Emerson.
Who is this "son of the thread"
you're talking about?
You gave those two hope
that there's another tracker here.
Miss, I didn't give them false hope.
They will actually be helped by…
- the son of the thread.
- Ah!
So, who is it?!
Me.
- Eh, you! you…
- [chuckles]
- You're always full of nonsense!
- [Emerson] Miss.
You gave those two women
false hope, poor thing--
Miss, I'm not kidding around.
I know what to do!
I've joined Atoy's missions many times.
I know this already!
I've joined about…
- [Cita] What?
- About… Twice. Two times!
Miss, I know what to do.
- That's easy for me!
- [claps hands together]
Really, huh?
Fine.
What do you do when searching
for a missing person or thing?
Aside from praying to--
- [Cita] Mmm? Mmm?
- to Saint Anthony of Padua.
- [Emerson] What…
- What?
Eh…
[sneaky music playing]
Oh, no. Oh, no.
- You nailed my irritation!
- Wait-- I know--
- You really nailed my irritation!
- [Emerson] I know, miss, I know!
Miss, eh.
- [Cita] What?
- I'll call Atoy.
I'll ask him for help.
That's better, otherwise,
- you will get it from me.
- Atoy.
Atoy.
[music fades]
[camera shutter snapping]
[suspicious music playing]
[phone ringing]
- [line ringing]
- Hmm, you think you're so clever.
Miss, it's ringing. Be quiet.
[line ringing]
[phone rings]
- Hello?
- Ah! He… Hello?
Atoy.
'Toy, please help me.
Please.
What happened to you?
You sound like your life is in danger.
It is in danger, in Miss Cita's hands.
Serves you right.
- Huh?
- Nothing.
[Atoy] What's going on? What do you need?
No. Well, 'Toy, it's because, um…
Someone came here
asking for help, looking for you.
‪Uh…
But you weren't here.
They said they were robbed.
So, I volunteered.
What?!
[Emerson] Yes!
Because, of course, I felt bad for them.
They asked for help, and…
[Emerson] It's for a good cause.
Because the stolen money
was meant to build a school for children.
So, ‘Toy, what? Will you help…
Help me, ‘Toy, okay?
Will you help me?
[sneaky music playing]
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
There, huh. You said it, huh. Okay.
[in English] Step by step, ‘Toy, okay?
This will be a long talk.
Son of a thread.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[Atoy] Here's what you do.
There. Take a look.
- Take a look.
- Right.
[Atoy] Observe how the theft happened,
how they entered the place.
Look closely at the thief too.
Usually, their faces are covered, so…
look for other clues on their body.
Unbelievable.
We worked so hard to secure sponsorships,
to save money for the children.
Why are there people
who don't know how to fight fair?
Well, you know their day will come.
Here.
[in English] Sixty.
That's too expensive.
Make it 50!
Vegetables are pricey.
[in English] Fifty-five!
[in English] Fifty-six!
[in English] Fifty-three!
Fine!
[sneaky music playing]
Hey, wait!
No backing out, miss!
You already agreed!
If you back out now,
your luck might back out too!
You're a clever kid.
Can you teach me how to cook chop suey?
Wow! You haggled
and now you want a tutorial.
Where's your mother?
Why don't you ask her to teach you?
Whose child are you?
Mama Olga. The one who lives there.
Oh, I know Olga.
Are you her child?
Yes, we just reunited.
We were separated when I was a baby.
But now she found me.
Wow, like a soap opera!
But Olga never told us
she had a missing child.
Where did you come from, kid?
How old are you?
[Charmi] Oh my! Oh!
Ibyang, what are you doing here?
Sister Faye,
I just bought food for dinner.
Oh, Ibyang.
Don't talk to gossips,
or you'll end up like them.
Go home now.
Your mama won't like this. Go home now.
[in English] Go.
Hey, Charmi! Why did she call you Faye?
Hey, you!
That's my second name, Charmielyn Faye!
You're such a gossip.
You ask too many questions!
I forgot what I was buying.
Here, here! Give me plantains.
I'll make pot roast today.
Okay.
There, let's put it in a plastic bag.
Oh, come on. Okay.
- Here.
- Hmm.
- Take care of it.
- Yes.
Ma'am, who do you think
would be interested in this money?
Who else knows about it?
Our staff.
But they've all been investigated.
No one suddenly resigned
or changed lifestyle.
We have one suspect.
It's hard to accuse anyone without proof.
Then make an accusation.
It's just us here anyway.
The ex-president of Build for Kids.
He was bitter when he was replaced.
He swore we'd never have
a successful project without him.
[pensive music playing]
Do you have a picture of this person?
Yes we have. Wait.
Here he is. There.
Kevin Martinez.
Um, good afternoon,
Ma'am Malou, Ma'am Odette.
[Emerson] Uh…
Sir, are you investigating the theft?
Any updates?
Still none.
Honestly, the longer this case drags on,
the smaller the chance
we'll recover the money.
Most likely, it was already spent.
- [sobbing]
- [tense music playing]
[music fades]
Brother Atoy left right away.
We didn't even get to talk.
Just wait for him to come back.
But what if he doesn't?
His missions are dangerous.
I only feel at ease when I'm with him,
when I'm driving him.
At least then, I know he's safe.
[suspicious music playing]
[Atoy] Who's that?
Later, brother! Let's go!
[gunshots]
Hey!
But now it seems unlikely
he'll take me along again.
Wait, wait, wait.
You said you're Brother Atoy's driver,
and his missions are dangerous.
Does that mean he's the boss you mentioned
in Endless Nights before?
Huh?
The one in the shootout,
then jumped out of the car?
That was Brother Atoy?
I never said that.
Karla, wait.
Don't deny it.
I won't tell anyone.
It's me, after all.
That's the problem. It's you.
Well, you did slip a bit
to Brother Atoy last time.
It won't happen again.
[in English] Promise?
[light music playing]
[in English] Promise.
[in English] Okay.
But Brother Atoy's side job is top secret.
I didn't want you to know,
because isn't your dad his enemy?
They almost killed each other.
I won't tell Dad.
Actually, I prefer what Brother Atoy does.
Exposing Endless Nights.
At least he shut it down
and stopped the boxing match
of little persons.
You know…
you're really different from your dad.
Let's promise each other
that whatever conflicts happen
between your brother and my dad,
our friendship won't be affected.
We're solid.
[in English] Okay?
[in English] Promise?
[chuckles softly]
There.
[in English] Promise.
[music fades]
[suspicious music playing]
[chuckles softly]
Karla, let's stay here first.
[Karla] Why?
[music fades]
What? What?
You see I'm concentrating here.
You've been replaying that over and over.
So? Did the ending change?
Here!
I can't focus!
That sweeping is irritating!
Sweep later.
Just admit, you're too ambitious!
You're acting like the Master Cutter.
Atoy's level is here.
Yours is way down here!
You can't reach it.
How high?
Here, you can't reach it.
It's too high.
Oh, you have a problem with being small.
But you're only a little taller than me!
Here, oh… Come on.
Here, oh.
Oh, try to reach my ear.
[chuckles]
Try to reach my ear.
You, do that later.
Just sweep later!
There you go again.
Because there's still so much mess!
[in English] Special delivery!
Two orders of pares!
Huh? Two?
Oh, why?
Did you order for me too?
No, I'll eat it all myself.
Come on. Ouch! What the hell? Ouch!
Stop!
[in English] Sorry, sorry.
- Sorry, it was just a joke.
- [in English] You're welcome.
It was just a joke.
[sneaky music playing]
Put it there, Ame!
There, oh!
Why do you have CCTV footage here?
[action music playing]
Do you have a mission?
But isn't Atoy gone?
I can't solve this without Atoy.
Maybe Ame is right.
Maybe I should back out of this mission!
Ah, don't! What?! What! what?!
You've been…
Ame, give me that pares!
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[music fades]
[electronic blipping]
We found the suspect
in the five-million robbery.
Here's what you do.
You need to go to that shop.
[Atoy] Pretend to be customers
or whatever you want.
The important thing is to get inside
and gather information
about the money from that person.
[Atoy] Just make sure you're not noticed.
Who's that? Come out…
if you don't want to get hurt.
UP NEXT
[in English] You are not a suspect, no.
[in English] We actually have
a picture of the suspect.
[Audrey, in English] Really?
[Samir, in English]
He's a master of disguise.
[in English] Do you know this man?
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪